Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection [dates] PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 18xx-20xx
  - Subseries IX.F. Medical/Health (incl AIDS)
    - New York Regional Blood Bank Program, 1956 (Folder 09-09)
      Donate blood poster sponsored by the American Red Cross New York Regional Blood Program. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: Apr 18 1956.
    - Poster for play, "As Is"., 1985 (Folder 09-11)
      Poster designed by Fraver. As Is was awarded the 1985 Best Play of the Year by Drama Desk. It was at the Lyceum Theater, written by William M. Hoffman, and directed by Marshall W. Mason.
    - Day Without Art poster [AIDS], 1989 (Folder 09-11)
      Day Without Art, 1989, poster created by M Plus M Incorporated and designed by Visual AIDS. PR55 removal slip in folder: removed 8/12/2021 for in house Exhibition, "Art for Change".
    - "AIDS. It's not a problem anymore - right, Mom?", 1998 (Folder 09-11)
      Day Without Art, December 1, 1998, poster designed by Visual AIDS. Digital Pre-Press/Production: Katz Digital Technologies, Inc. and printed by Louis Sherman & Co.
    - "AIDS is over, right? (or maybe, you should read the fine print)", 1998 (Folder 09-11)
  - Subseries IX.G. Books/Libraries/Education
    - Celebration of 50 years for the American Library Association and Public Libraries, 1926 (Folder 09-19)
      Poster by E.A. Spuehler promoting Public Libraries as an American contribution to Civilization.
    - Advertisement for New York YMCA Schools Day and Evening Classes, [1935] (Folder 09-19)
      Poster included a pocket to hold pamphlets to take. There were classes for men and women and included Evening High School and Day Preparatory School for Boys. Acquisition date (?) on back, Sept. 4, 1935.
    - Advertisement for The Bronx Preparatory School on East Tremont Avenue, [1939] (Folder 09-19)
      Advertised that it was the only school in the Bronx approved by the Board of Regents. Jacob Grossman, B.S., D.D.S. was the principal. In pencil on back, "E.B. Childs/39".
    - Bronx Union Branch YMCA Evening Course Enrollment, [1939] (Folder 09-19)
      Courses included topics in business, technical, languages, cultural, and academic with the promise that invested evenings would pay big dividends. In pencil on back, "E.B. Childs/39".
    - "Men of the World, Exhibition of Sculpture by Malvina Hoffman", 1942 (Folder 09-19)
      Exhibition sponsored by the Coordinating Council of French Relief Societies, Inc. and included "Photo-Murals showing world map and all the races of the world". Acquisition date (?) on back, Dec. 28, 1942.
    - Publication announcement for "The World of Washington Irving" by Van Wyck Brooks, 1944 (Folder 09-19)
      E.P. Dutton & Company, Inc. published the book. Acquisition date (?) on back, Sept. 14, 1944.
    - Skira Art Books advertisement for its "History of Modern Painting" book, c.1950 (Folder 09-19)
      Poster was printed in France and features the front cover of the book.
    - Skira Art Books advertisement for its "Italian Painting: The Creators of the Renaissance" book, c.1950 (Folder 09-19)
      Poster was printed in France and features the front cover artwork.
    - Advertisement for the Summer/Winter Sessions of the Interamerican School of Spanish in Mexico, 1951 (Folder 09-19)
      School was the only under graduate and graduate school of its kind in Mexico. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back, Nov 7 1951.
    - "Use Your Library ... then VOTE", 1952 (Folder 09-19)
      2 copies. Poster was contributed by "Childrens Press, publishers of the famous "You" books and other fine educational materials". Acquisition date(?) stamped on the back of both copies, Sep 8 1952.
    - "New York is Book Country. September 16, 1979" (Folder 09-19)
      Design by Barbara Hennessy, illustration by Maurice Sendak, production by Eileen G. Schwartz, printing and production courtesy of Viking Penguin, Inc., and distribution courtesy of Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc. Net proceeds benefit Children's Services, New York Public Library.
    - "Theft of Books or Manuscripts? FOLLOW These Steps Immediately!", [1983]
      Poster was sponsored by the Antiquarian Booksellers Association of American and advertised its pamphlet explaining the international security network. In pencil on back, Gift (?) 1983.
    - "New York City - It's A Great College Town", 1987 (Folder 09-19)
      Poster created by graphic artist, Tony Graham. In pencil on back, "Bought at Newmark Gallery, 3rd. Avenue by Wendy Shadwell, Nov. 1987".
    - Laguardia Community College/CUNY Newsposter, "Our Secret is Success", undated (Folder 09-19)
      Two sided poster. First side advertises the college and explains admission procedure. Other side explains college majors.
  - Subseries IX.H. United Jewish Appeal
    - "Dollars for Survival", 1948 (Folder 09-17)
      2 copies of portrait-oriented poster and 2 copies of landscape-oriented poster. Poster was lithographed in the U.S.A. United Jewish Appeal for $250,000,000 minimum. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back of all copies, Nov 22 1948.
    - "For the Greatest Homecoming in History", 1949 (Folder 09-17)
      United Jewish Campaign for $250,000,000 (minimum). Poster features photograph of people on a ship waving Israeli flags. Acquisition date (?) on back, May 6, 1949.
    - "For the greatest homecoming in history. Make Their Homecoming Your Birthday Gift to the State of Israel.", 1949 (Folder 09-17)
      United Jewish Appeal campaign for $250,000,000 (minimum). Poster features photograph of people on a ship waving Israeli flags. Similar to above poster but features added language. Acquisition date (?) on back, May 6, 1949.
    - "For the greatest homecoming in history", 1949 (Folder 09-17)
      United Jewish Appeal campaign for $250,000,000 (minimum). 3 copies. All feature photograph of a line of people carrying bags. Copy 1 is a very large poster, Copy 2 is a portrait-oriented poster, Copy 3 is a landscape-oriented poster. Acquisition date (?) on back of all copies, May 6, 1949.
  - Subseries IX.I. Israel Emergency Fund
    - "Miracles Through Unity - Purim 1974" (Folder 09-18)
      Poster created by Pinchas Shaar for The Israel Emergency Fund.
    - Advertisement for program, "Discover a people called Israel", 1975 (Folder 09-18)
      Program sponsored by The United Jewish Appeal's Overseas Programs.
    - "The Fifth Cup", undated (Folder 09-18)
      Poster is sponsored by This Year in Jerusalem. An appeal to renew dedication to the vision of life of freedom and dignity for all our people.
    - "Therefore Choose Life", undated (Folder 09-18)
      Israel Emergency Fund appeal.
    - "Operation Joshua: Scout the Land", undated (Folder 09-18)
      The Operation Joshua trips were sponsored by The Student Coordinatimg Committee for the Israel Emergency Fund Tours for College Students program.
    - The Israel Emergency Fund Appeal poster, undated (Folder 09-18)
      Poster includes a quote from Elie Wiesel and includes the slogan, "We Are One".
    - "Don't Stop" Israel Emergency Fund Appeal poster, undated (Folder 09-18)
    - "Be Counted Among The Committed" Israel Emergency Fund appeal poster, undated (Folder 09-18)
    - "Immigration Absorption Youth Education" poster, undated (Folder 09-18)
      Poster includes inspiring statements. "We Are One", "Proclaim Liberty", "Unity, Leadership, Community, Responsibility".
  - Subseries IX.J. Car Cards / Subway Ads
    - Advertisement for Wrigley's Spearmint Gum - "Ride Relaxed - Work Relaxed", c.1930s (Folder 09-24)
      "Litho in U.S.A. 915-A". Subway advertisement features two smiling young women with an office building and a secretarial desk in the background. Although unsigned, probably by Dorothy and Otis Shepard.
    - Advertisement for Frigidaire "Thrifty-30" Electric Ranges, c.1953 (Folder 09-24)
      "Litho in U.S.A. CAR-1-54" Advertisement features a housewife in front of open oven range with a roasting turkey and a ruler - "Only 30 inches wide!" Running along the bottom of the advertisement, "Burton's Stove Store 502-6 Burnet St."
    - Car Card: Campaign to approve a New Constitution to allow for parochial school funding, 1967 (Folder 09-25)
      Car Card was sponsored by Citizens for Educational Freedom, Inc. Poster features a photograph of many parochial schoolchildren denied aid under the U.S. Constitution. In pencil on front, "Vote No". Stamped on back, Sep 30 1976.
    - Car Card: Campaign to approve a New Constitution to allow for parochial school funding, 1967 (Folder 09-25)
      Car Card was sponsored by Citizens for Educational Freedom, Inc. Poster features a photograph of a child denied Speech Therapy aid under the U.S. Constitution. Stamped on back, Sep 30 1976.
    - Car Card: Campaign to approve a New Constitution to allow for parochial school funding, 1967 (Folder 09-25)
      Car Card was sponsored by Citizens for Educational Freedom, Inc. Poster features a photograph of a child denied reading education aid under the U.S. Constitution. Stamped on back, Sep 30 1976.
    - Car Card: Campaign to approve a New Constitution to allow for parochial school funding, 1967 (Folder 09-25)
      Car Card was sponsored by Citizens for Educational Freedom, Inc. Poster features a photograph of a child denied psychological aid under the U.S. Constitution. On front, "Education Freedom" is crossed out and under is "Papism". Stamped on back, Sep 30 1976.
    - Car Card: Advertisement for Income Tax Loan from Manufacturers Hanover Trust, 1967 (Folder 09-25)
      Poster features three colorful dragons (City, State, Federal taxes) and dragon slaying banker. Stamped on back, Sep 30 1976. In pencil on back, 1967?
    - Advertisement in Spanish for Panadol with spokesman Pele., c. 1970s (Folder 09-24)
      Advertisement features two images of a young Pele in a soccer uniform.
    - Advertisement for Black Flag Roach Motel, 1982 (Folder 09-24)
      Poster copyrighted by Boyle-Midway Div. Features the slogan, "Roaches check in ... but they don't check out!" and colorful graphics of bugs.
    - MTA Poetry in Motion posters, c.1993 (Folder 09-24)
      2 posters with similar banners across the top. One features an excerpt from the poem, "Coal" by Audre Lorde; the other features a poem by Joseph Brodsky. Both were printed by the MTA in cooperation with the Poetry Society of America.
  - Subseries IX.K. Exhibitions (Museums, Galleries, etc.)
    - Exhibition poster for Mr. Currier and Mr. Ives Diverting Panorama, 1932 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition of lithographs to celebrate the 200th anniversary of the birth of George Washington and the 100th birthday of Louis Maurer at The Old Print Shop. On back, "Gift of Eugenia Maurer Fuerstenberg (daughter of Louis Maurer) June 30, 1939".
    - Exhibition poster for "Forty Five Years of French Art", 1941 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster produced by W.P.A., and exhibition held at the Brooklyn Museum. Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct. 3, 1941.
    - Exhibition poster for "Men Against Fire", 1942 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster made by N.Y.C. WPA War Services. Special exhibition at the Museum of the City, 5th Avenue at 104th Street. Acquisition date(?) on back, Dec. 28, 1942.
    - Exhibition poster for "Old Views of American Colleges", 1945 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition at The Grolier Club. Image is of "A Prospect of the Colleges in Cambridge in New England".
    - Exhibition poster for "History of Medicine in Art, Free Exhibition of Prints", 1946 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition held at NYU College of Medicine. Image of "Fever and Ague" by Rowlandson, 18th Century. Acquisition date(?), in pencil, April 6, 1946.
    - Exhibition poster for "Freedom Exhibit", 1950 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition was held at Freedom House, Willkie Memorial Building, 20 West 40th Street, New York. Image is of mural by Clinton Brown. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Nov 22 1950.
    - Exhibition poster for "A Medieval Treasury: New Exhibition of Rare and Fabulous Works of Art at The Cloisters", 1951 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at The Cloisters, Fort Tryon Park. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Nov 7 1951.
    - Exhibition poster for "Art Exhibition Kingston's 300th Anniversary", 1952 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition held at George Washington School, Kingston, NY, featuring a wide diversity of American Art. Aquisition date(?) on front and back, July 1952.
    - Exhibition poster for "Summer Art Show at Hofstra College, Hempstead, L.I.", 1952 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by Haydock. The Summer Art show featured masterpieces from the Metropolitan Museum of Art (El Greco, Van Dyck, Rembrandt...). Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Jul 24 1952.
    - Exhibition poster for "John James Audubon 1785-1851", 1960 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster: "Moulot imp.". Exhibition held at Centre Culturel Americain, Paris.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Landscape of Change: Views of Rural New England 1790-1865", 1976 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at Old Sturbridge Village, Massachusetts. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, May 18 1976.
    - Exhibition poster for "Bevan Davies", 1976 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition held at the Broxton Gallery, Westwood, CA. Poster features photograph of building at the northeast corner of Broome Street and Broadway (see note on back). On back, stamped Mar 12 1976.
    - Exhibition poster for "American Illustration: 1800 to the Present", 1977 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at the Mint Museum of Art, sponsored by Exxon, and circulated by The American Federation of Arts.
    - Exhibition poster for "Reginald Marsh: The Art of Popular Entertainment", 1977 (Folder 09-27)
      The poster features a Marsh engraving, "Merry-Go-Round", 1943, NYPL. Poster numbered 25/90. The exhibition was held at the Vincent Astor Gallery, The New York Public Library at Lincoln Center. Alongside the poster is a exhibition program. On back, "Gift, Malkin, 1984".
    - Exhibition poster for "Children in America", 1978 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at The High Museum of Art, Atlanta. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Jan 20 1979.
    - Exhibition poster for "Alexander Alland", 1979 (Folder 09-26)
      2 copies. Poster by Permild & Rosengreen. Exhibition held at Nordjyllands Kunstmuseum and Kunstindustrimuseet. Image is of Brooklyn Bridge.
    - Exhibition poster for "Art Documentation and Computers", 1979 (Folder 09-26)
      3 copies. Poster by Vittorio Fiorucci. All three copies have same graphic bird image. Copy 1 has text: "Picture Division Departement de L'Iconographie; Public Archives Canada Archives publiques Canada". Copy 2 has text: "National Inventory Programme Programme du Repertoire National; National Museums Musees nationaux Canada". On back of Copy 2 "To: Gail Marciano". Copy 3 has text: "Art Documentation and Computers Ordinateurs et Normes Descriptives en Art; Novermber 1-3, 1979 Du 1 Au 3 Novembre 1979 Ottawa, Canada".
    - Exhibition poster for "Panorama of the Great Metropolis", 1980 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Pat Mulvaney and Larry Zim. Inaugural exhibit at the Zim-Lerner Design Gallery in cooperation with the New York Design Fair and featured paintings, photographs, prints, and artifacts (The Larry Zim World Fairs Collection) from the New York World Fairs of 1853, 1901, 1909,1939, and 1964.
    - Exhibition poster for "Tons of Type: American Letterpress Broadsides of the 18th and 19th Centuries", 1980 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by David Gibson. Exhibition held at The Yale Center for American Art and Material Culture. Back side has text and images.
    - Exhibition poster for "Printmaking in Canada: The Earliest Views and Portraits", 1980 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by ROM (Royal Ontario Museum) and features an image, "Notre Dame Street Montreal." published by A.Bourne Montreal, 1830. Exhibition traveled from the Royal Ontario Museum to the Musee McCord Museum to the Public Archives of Canada.
    - Exhibition poster for "P.B. Wight: Architect, Contractor, and Critic, 1838-1925", 1981 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Michael Glass (Chicago) and printed by Eastern Press (New Haven). Exhibition held at National Academy of Design, New York, and image features a proposed decoration by P.B. Wight for the central stairwell of the National Academy of Design (unexecuted), reprint courtesy of The Burnham Library of Architecture, The Art Institute of Chicago. Along with the poster is a press release about a lecture series on the exhibition. On back, in pencil, "Gift from National Academy of Design, 1981".
    - Exhibition poster for "Medicine & Pharmacy: 100 Years of Poster Art", 1981 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held in commemoration of the 100th anniversary of The Albany College of Pharmacy and held at the New York State Museum, The State Education Department. Exhibited items were from the Collection of William H. Helfand. On back, in pencil, Gift of William Helfand, October 7, 1981.
    - Exhibition poster for "Acquisitions 1973-1980. George Eastman House", 1981 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by IMP/GEH (International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House). Image is of an "Untitled" autochrome by Edward Steichen, ca. 1911, Gift of Joanna T. Steichen.
    - Exhibition poster for "Keith Haring Drawings", 1982 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition at Tony Shafrazi Gallery. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Beth Eddy 2013".
    - Exhibition poster for "Particulars: Selections From The Miller-Plummer Collection of Photography", 1983 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Robert Meyer Design, Inc. and copyrighted by IMP/GEH (International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House). Image is of "Julia Margaret Cameron, (And Enid Sang), 1874, Albumen Print."
    - Exhibition poster for "Gardens of the Gilded Age: New York State Victorian Gardens", c.1983 (Folder 09-26)
      "Design of Posterlog: William Padgett. Title page logo design: Beverly Giannetto." Exhibition was organized at The 1890 House Museum and Center for Victorian Arts, Cortland, NY, and circulated by the Gallery Association of New York State. Exhibition funded by grant from New York State Council on the Arts; also the Homer Garden Club, Mrs. Julian W. Davidson, Mrs. Frank A. Plummer, and the Institute of Museum Services. Support also from NEA, NEH, Amerada Hess Coporation, Hess Foundation, Lehman Brothers Kuhn Loeb, Inc., Marine Midland Bank, NY Telephone Company, JC Penney, Sykes Datatronic, Inc. Images of gardens on back.
    - Exhibition poster for "Architecture in Brooklyn: An Eclectic Overview", 1983 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at the Museum of the Borough of Brooklyn at Brooklyn College. Image is of a George B. Post watercolor drawing of Williamsburg Savings Bank, reprinted with permission of The New-York Historical Society.
    - Exhibition poster for "Palace of Commerce, The United States Custom House", 1983 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by Keith Godard and Janet Giampietro of Works, Text by Deborah Nevins, and Copyright by The New York Landmarks Conservancy. The exhibition sponsored by the New York Landmarks Conservancy, funded by the NEA, the New York State Council on the Arts, and the Custom House Institute. Image of Custom House o front, images, timeline, and text on back.
    - Exhibition poster for "Phototypes, Whitney Museum of American Art, Downtown Branch", 1983 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at Federal Hall National Memorial through cooperation of Federal Hall Associates and the National Park Service, Manhattan Sites. Image is a 1934 Margaret Bourke-White photograph, "Ornamental Gargoyle, Chrysler Building" The Museum of Modern Art, Gift of the photographer. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, May 12 1983.
    - Exhibition poster for "Building Brooklyn Bridge: The Design and Construction 1867-1883" (Folder 09-26)
      2 copies. The Centennial Exhibition was at the National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution, and supported by American Society of Civil Engineers; American Society of Civil Engineers - Metropolitan Section; Citibank/Citicorp; Mueser, Rutledge, Johnston & Desimone; F.W. Roebling III; Society of Women Engineers and Steinman, Boynton, Gronquist & Birdsall.
    - Exhibition poster for "Terminal New York", 1983 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by John Feidelson; photography by Bill Jacobson. The Art Exhibition was held at the Harborside Industrial Center (Brooklyn Army Terminal) and sponsored by AAA Art, Brooklyn Art and Culture Association, Materials for the Arts, New York City Public Development Corporation, Public Art Fund, and United Color.
    - Exhibition poster for "Brooklyn Bridge: 100th Anniversary 100 Photographs", 1983 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by Kari Ann Pagnano and features a photograph by Arthur Leipzig. The Group Show was held at the Midtown Y Gallery.
    - Exhibition poster for "Images of Brooklyn Bridge: A Centennial Salute by Seven Photographers", 1983 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by Bill Hine and printed by Pioneer Moss Reproductions, Inc. Copyright held by The Municipal Art Society of NY which also presented the exhibition. The seven photographers were Jeff Perkell, Peter B. Kaplan, Andrew Moore, Jan Staller, Michael George, Mark Feldstein, and Bill Hine. Curated by Mary Black.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Naval War College: A Century of Excellence", 1984 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibitions commemorating the 100th anniversary of the College and the history of the Navy in Narragansett Bay. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Feb 5 1985.
    - Exhibition poster for "Made on Staten Island: Agriculture, Industry, and Suburban Living in the City (1800-1984) (Folder 09-26)
      Inaugural exhbition held at The Historical Museum at Richmondtown, Staten Island Historical Society/Richmondtown Restoration. Grants provided by New York State Council on the Arts and J.M. Kaplan Fund. On back, in pencil, "November 1984 Gift of Charles Sachs, Staten Is. Hist. Soc."
    - Exhibition poster for "The Legacy of Lafayette", 1984 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Leone Design Group. Image of Lafayette - "B.leClair after L.Barre. Marquis de la Fayette ... gift of D. Weston Darby, Jr., 1983. Fraunces Tavern Museum". Exhibition held at Fraunces Tavern Museum, owned and operated by the Sons of the Revolution in the State of New York, Inc. On back, "Gift of Jean Burnham Nov 01 1984.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Art of Politics", 1984 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Pushpin, Lubalin, Peckolick, Inc. Exhibition held at Museum of the Borough of Brooklyn, Brooklyn College. Poster designed to look like newpaper frontpage. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Oct 16 1984.
    - Exhibition poster for Louis Jay Suckle - Cafeteria: Portraits from Dubrow's", 1984 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster by WalkerPrint, London. Exhibition held at Popular Photography on Park Avenue. On back, stamped Sep 14 1984.
    - Exhibition poster for "American Prints: 1914-1941", 1985 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Carl Zahn and printed by The Meriden Gravure Co., Connecticut. Copyrighted by Museum of Fine Arts, Boston (also exhibit held there) and image is of George Bellows' "A Stag at Sharkey's" 1917. Lithograph. Bequest of W.G.Russell Allen.
    - Exhibition poster for "Twentieth-Century Afro-American Artists", 1985 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Gianettino & Meredith, Inc., and Photo of artwork, "Fort Jesus (Totem) 1984" by Vincent Smith, by Sarah Wells. Exhibition held at The Newark Museum.
    - Exhibition poster for "Wine Celebration and Ceremony", 1985 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition held at Cooper-Hewitt Museum, The Smithsonian Institute's National Museum of Design, and made possible by grant from Moet & Chandon.